<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<wpiedata>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Kinsta Feeds 300 Homeless for Thanksgiving]]></title>
    <descriptions><![CDATA[This year we decided to feed the homeless here in Los Angeles, by donating food to Second Harvest, one of the largest food banks in the country.

We went to Costco and purchased 200 servings of mashed potatoes, sweet potatoes, rolls, stuffing, and baked beans. It ended up being 140 pounds worth of food as weighed at the donation site, and they said since we donated so many items they could easily stretch it to make 300 meals when paired with the annual turkey donations they receive.

]]></descriptions>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Kinsta Kingpin: Interview With Steve Zehngut]]></title>
    <descriptions><![CDATA[I started Zeek Interactive more than 20 years ago to create interactive games. Over those 20 years, Zeek worked in Shockwave, Flash, CD-ROM, and finally web and mobile. Once we started creating websites, WordPress became the obvious choice for a CMS. We started the Orange County WordPress meetup to find other local developers to hire to offset our workload, and it’s grown into a strong community of people improving existing skills and teaching new skills to others.

Q2: What should readers know about Zeek Interactive, & what kinds of clients are a good fit?

Our clients are companies that want more than a website. They want the strategy to go with it. These are companies whose business IS their site; it’s how they generate their revenue. So we help them do that, while also helping them with application and mobile development so that they have everything they need.]]></descriptions>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Kinsta Kingpin: Interview With Chris Lema
]]></title>
    <descriptions><![CDATA[Q2: Which WordPress events will you most likely be attending in 2016?

I’ll be speaking at WooConf – a conference just focused on WooCommerce. I’ll also be running CaboPress – but dates haven’t been announced yet. Other than that, I’ll be organizing WordCamp San Diego, and will be speaking at WordCamp Milwaukee.

Q3: What’s your day-to-day like at Crowd Favorite?

My mornings are in meetings – whether it’s with my team leads, with my entire development team, or with our exec team. My afternoons are spent either on calls, or producing material – from white papers to estimates and quotes to reports (findings) for clients as part of a discovery process. So half the day is very people-centric and half the day is just me and my computer.

Q4: How has your experience been with Rainmaker?

I really enjoy Rainmaker. It’s a perfect solution for a lot of different kinds of people. In this case, for my blog, since I wanted to limit my focus on simply content creation over feature development, it’s been great.

Q5: If you wanted to host a site that wasn’t a good fit for Rainmaker, what features do you feel are must-have for any managed WP host?

The managed host game continues to change]]></descriptions>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Kinsta Kingpin: Interview With Kiko Doran, Co-Founder of Prestige Conference
]]></title>
    <descriptions><![CDATA[roll with the punches and move on. Luckily, I was able to learn this lesson while planning WordCamps Minneapolis 2013 and 2014.

Q3: How does your Prestige conference differentiate itself from others in the WordPress space?

One way we’re different is Prestige is 100% focused on running your business. The advice I give to speakers when we are working on session topics is, “Give a 5 year younger version of yourself some business advice.” We are all strong in some areas and weak in others. Prestige is here to give you a few more tools to use in the growth of your business. We also produce the best-designed swag around!

Prestige Conference is 100% focused on running your business. #wordpress #startup.
CLICK TO TWEET
Q4: What do you look for in a city when planning a conference?

When choosing a city, we look at many different elements. We like cities that have an amazing tech community and also have plenty to do within walking distance of the venue/hotels. It costs a lot to travel to conferences – we want to make sure that our attendees can also have fun during their down time. A few of us on the planning team are baseball junkies. If we can catch a game leading into the event, we love that city even more!

Q5: How should conferences work, in contrast to how they do now?

There’s a trend with conferences just collecting speakers. There’s no rhyme or reason to the selection and you might even have two of the same or similar talks back to back, at the same event. Events should be planned by taking time to get to know what your speakers are passionate about and then helping to create a schedule that is “in sync.” This all promotes content that is well rounded and bound to connect, in some facet, with everyone in attendance.

Q6: If your best friend was going to start a conference, what basic advice would you give them?


Want to know how we increased our traffic over 1000%?
Join 20,000+ others who get our weekly newsletter with insider WordPress tips!

Subscribe Now
Don’t do it! Haha! With all joking aside make sure you have the proper support to make it a success the first time. Remember that you have three different perspectives to consider to make your event a success. Create a great experience for the speakers, sponsors, and attendees; then you’ll have a successful event.

I did a podcast with, my favorite publisher of business content in the WordPress ecosystem, Matt Medeiros on this very topic. It was right after our first event but the information is still true today.


Q7: In your opinion, what will conferences look like in 2030?

Sadly, we’re moving towards more virtual conferences. While it’s great to be able to share info with people across the globe, you miss out on the in person networking that happens at live events. I’ve had countless people thank me for the knowledge they’ve gained from the first three Prestige Conferences. Almost every one of them has mentioned the open sharing of information between “should be competitors.” Take advantage of being able to talk to these brilliant business minds in a casual environment!

Q8: What did you think about the first WordCamp US in Philadelphia?

WordCamp US was incredible! I’m not surprised the planning team did such an amazing job – Philadelphia has always been one of my favorite camps. I honestly think they should just leave it in Philadelphia every year. The convention center has a lot of room for us to grow into it. Let’s move it to a warmer time of year and leave it in Philly!

Q9: How long have you been working with WordPress and what peaked your curiosity about it?

I started using WordPress in 2008 because a band I was in needed a website and I wanted to find a way to manage content better than I had been doing with static sites, up until that point. The rest is history… Now I barely play music but I use WordPress every day.

Q10: If you were in charge of the self-hosted WordPress software, what changes would you make?

We’ve gone off the rails. I thought we were talking about conferences… I’ll keep it to conferences then for my answer. I’d change that WordCamps are run through a non-profit foundation. I would like to see it run as a “for-profit” business. I think that change would have a domino effect helping us overcome many hurdles currently in place. Just one example… Sponsor benefits are virtually non existent when donating to support WordCamps under the current structure. We should be able to promote the companies that help us to put on the amazing conferences around WordPress. I could go on and on but this probably would deserve its own set of 10 questions.

I'd change that WordCamps are run through a non-profit foundation. I'd like to see it run as a for-profit business.
CLICK TO TWEET
Also, I’d tell everyone to go to PrestigeConf.com tomorrow Wednesday Feb 17th at 9am Pacific time for our super early bird tickets. There are only 25 available and they’ll go fast!

]]></descriptions>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title><![CDATA[Kinsta Kingpin: Interview with Ben Pines]]></title>
    <descriptions><![CDATA[Q1: What is your background, & how did you first get involved with WordPress?
In 2006, I started my marketing career as an in an SEO agency. It was the wild west era of SEO, back when all you had to do in order to get that sweet Google traffic was to build a content-rich website and linking back to client’s site. That’s exactly what I did. I actually managed to get the WordPress website which I built for the sole purpose of my client’s promotion high ranking. This was when I realized the potential of WordPress. I remember an argument with my boss, one of the top SEO figures in Israel, who claimed WordPress was a platform built only for blogs. In his view, it was not suited for other types of sites. I’m glad I stuck with my conviction to stick with WordPress.]]></descriptions>
  </item>
</wpiedata>
